Loi Nguyen

<u>linkedin.com/in/loinguyen01835</u>| ■519-781-4386 | Mloi.nguyen.01835@gmail.com | <u>github.com/loinguyen</u>

Summary

With 8+ years of experience, I am a skilled full-stack developer who has worked in multiple countries including the USA, Singapore, and Vietnam. My passion lies in coding and continuously expanding my knowledge of web development and emerging technologies. I possess a strong aptitude for quick adaptation to new technologies and actively seek challenges to enhance my skill set.

Skills

Programming Language: Java | Python | JavaScript | TypeScript | SQL

Web Framework: Spring Boot | Spring MVC | Spring Security | Bootstrap | Angular | React.js | Firebase | Flask | Node.js | RESTful APIs

Database: MongoDB | Oracle DB | Neo4J

Management Process: Scrum | Kanban | JIRA | Trello | Test-driven development

Development Tool: Jenkin | Git | Subversion | Crucible | Docker | Figma

Project

UWConnect: Frontend Developer

04/2023

- Developed a social platform to help University of Waterloo students match with peers for recreational and academic purposes.
- Recommended matches based on user's profile or filter (course, faculty and hobbies etc.).
- Integrated CometChat UI Kits, SDKs and APIs to provide matched users with a real-time chatroom.
- Tech stacks: React, Flask, MongoDB and Docker.
- https://uwconnect650.onrender.com/

Education

Master of Engineering, Electrical and Computer Engineering University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON, Canada

05/2022 - Expected 08/2023

Bachelor of Software Engineering FPT University, Hanoi, Vietnam

09/2009 - 06/2012

Experience _

Full-Stack Developer

Morgan Stanley

Singapore

10/2018 - 04/2022

- Conducted analysis on system design to upgrade a center financial report portal to modern web framework
- Responsible for creating new framework to translate standard web UI to printable format.
- Optimized the report portal which helped reduce greatly all manual, time-consuming tasks of the reporting team.
- Managed project task follows Scrum standard

Software Developer & Consultant

FPT Asian Pacific

Singapore

11/2017 - 10/2018

- Responsible for maintaining a large products catalog system using Neo4J database
- Developed highly responsive APIs in Java that served critical subsystem
- Collaborated with Production team to deploy the product.
- Provided consultation on design and implementation of system
- Managed project tasked and assigned work for offshore team

Software Developer

FPT Software

Vietnam

06/2013 - 11/2017

- Optimized an existing recommendation Java system and provided customer support.
- Created automate testing script using Selenium and LISA that help improve the quality of deliverables
- Collaborated closely with international team in US and Singapore.
- Led a team of three members and managed tasked progress.